# PIERSON SCARBOROUGH

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

Designer turned creative software engineer with the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. Prior to being a software engineer, I worked as a Digital Marketing Manager for FINAFLEX where I managed the digital presence of a global nutrition brand.

### **EDUCATION**

**DigitalCrafts | Apr-Aug 2019**Certificate in Software Engineering

**University of Alabama | Aug 2013-May 2017** B.A. in Advertising

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Atlanta, Ga
pierson.site
706.483.0438
github.com/piersonscarborough
piersonscarborough@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/pierson-scarborough/

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Debugging, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Python, Node.js, React, Express, PostgreSQL, Sequalize, Bootstrap, Flexbox AWS, React Native, HTML, CSS

Illustrator, Photoshop, Lightroom, InDesign, PremierPro, Audition

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PORTFOLIO

#### BRAINZ | github.com/piersonscarborough/brainz

- A part of a 3-member team building a fully responsive aim-trainer
- BRAINZ is a retro inspired zombie first-person-shooter that allows the user to train their reaction time, track progress, and view top scores from other users to see who is the Top Undead Slayer
- The game features 3 difficulties along with a 4th hidden difficulty all designed to test even the most seasoned gamer. Flick gamemode in development
- Built with Javascript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL

#### showhunter | github.com/piersonscarborough/showhunter

- showhunter allows the user to enter a specific band or artist name and returns a series of nearby concerts where the band is playing along with suggestions of similar artists also playing in the area
- Project built with Javascript, CSS, HTMLL

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### FREELANCER | SEPT 2017-PRESENT

- Provide professional photography work
- Offer a variety of graphic design needs: logos/ branding, printables, infographics, etc.

#### FINAFLEX, Digital Brand Manager | AUG 2018-APR 2019

- Oversee marketing efforts and digital presence of the brand across all major platforms (Instagram, Facebook, e-commerce, etc.)
- Manage a dynamic team of 12+ sponsored athletes to ensure strong brand awareness within target audience
- Create original content and artwork to be used in packaging, displays, and digital marketing
- Maintain e-commerce site
- Analyze consumer engagement and sales along with dedicated research to the improvement of both figures

#### THOMAS WAGES, Manager | DEC 2017-JUL 2018

- Manage and create original content for all social media channels and social media advertising campaigns including: Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter
- Analyze sales and research ways to drive sales in-store and online
- Manage photoshoots by finding models, scheduling shoots, directing shoots, and taking/editing pictures
- Design signage, print-outs (brochures, business cards, etc.), logos, all graphics, and social media content
- Manage existing accounts: handle logistics of products, and act as main point of contact
- Schedule and assist with in-store appointments: from measuring to managing the production of their item